<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<main>
	<PageData>
	<MainHeading><![CDATA[]]></MainHeading>
		<SubHeading><![CDATA[11.7._Sensor Cloud Applications]]></SubHeading>
		<PageText>
			<pText><![CDATA[Sensors are very limited and specific to their applications or services when they are linked to a typical sensor network. Therefore, the number of organizations that can provide the sensor services are very limited. However, when the services of sensors move onto the cloud, it is possible to include them to realize a variety of applications. A number of services can be provided to the users for different applications such as health applications, environmental monitoring, industrial tasks (e.g., refining), surveillance, senior residents monitoring or even the applications that monitor the vibration in buildings during an earthquake.]]></pText>
		</PageText>
		<PageText>
			<pText><![CDATA[In the Sensor Cloud infrastructure, the sensors and service templates are constructed as catalog menu service on the cloud and the requesters can create new sensor services with the existing sensors in these service instances. For example, service requester can create a sensor service to analyze the impact of earthquake to each floor or room of the rehabilitation center or hospital, and at the same time it can also create sensor services to support older residents with the same set of sensors (virtualized sensors). This service will then help the caregiver to shift the older adults one by one into a safe place. Using the identical sensor services for healthcare, another service requester can create dissimilar sensor service to track the patient’s medicine intake and then to analyze the effectiveness of pills through the use of some selected healthcare sensors. Thus, the service requesters can be provided with new services using the same set of sensors on cloud service platforms. This will reduce the cost for resource usage and could have numerous elastic merits to it. Various Sensor Cloud applications that exist are given below.]]></pText>
		</PageText>
		<PageText>
			<pText><![CDATA[<ol class="DecimalNumberClass"><li><b>Nimbits -</b> Nimbits is a free and social service that is used to record and share sensor data on cloud. It is a cloud-based data processing service and is an open-source platform for the IoT (Internet of Things). We can feed the versatile numeric, text-based, JSON, GPS, or XML values by creating a data point in the cloud. The data points can be connected to Scalable Vector Graphic (SVG) process control, spreadsheets, diagrams, websites and more. Data points can also be configured to generate alerts data-relay to social networks and to perform calculations. Nimbits also provide an alert management mechanism, data compression mechanism and data calculation on received sensor data by employing some simple mathematical formulas.</li><li><b>Pachube Platform -</b> Pachube is one of the first online database service providers, which allows us to connect sensor data to the web. It is a real-time cloud-based platform for IoT with a scalable infrastructure that enables us to configure IoT products and services, store, share and discover real-time energy, environment and healthcare sensor data from devices and buildings around us. Pachube has a very interactive website for managing the sensor data and an open easily-accessible API. Pachube system provides free usage and has several number of interfaces for producing a sensor or mobile-based application for managing the sensor data within a cloud framework anytime.</li><li><b>IDigi -</b> IDigi is a machine-to-machine (M2M) Platform as a Service (PaaS) that minimizes the barriers to build scalable, secure and cost-effective solutions, which can bind the enterprise applications and device assets together. IDigi eases the connectivity of remote assets devices and provides all the tools to manage, store, connect and move the information across the enterprise irrespective of its reach. To simplify the remote device connectivity and integration, it uses connector software called IDigi Dia. Regardless of the network location, IDigi platform manages communication between remote device assets and enterprise applications.</li><li><b>ThingSpeak -</b> ThingSpeak is another open source IoT application and has an open API to store and retrieve data from device assets or things via LAN or using HTTP over the Internet. With this platform, location tracking applications, sensor logging applications and social network of device assets with proper update of its status can be created. ThingSpeak allows numeric data processing like averaging, time-scaling, rounding, median, summing and so forth to store and retrieve the numeric and alphanumeric data. ThingSpeak application features a JavaScript-based chart, read/ write API key management and a time-zone management</li></ol>]]></pText>
		</PageText>
		<PageText>
			<pText><![CDATA[Although the above services are able to visualize the sensor data and sensor-driven information, they are lacking secure access to data and interface availability for linking the external or mobile applications for further processing. It means that most of these aforementioned projects do not address the issues of data management and interoperability issues caused by heterogeneous data resources found in the present modern environmental tracking or electronic healthcare systems. But introducing these aforementioned works with Cloud computing infrastructure may overcome the issues related to heterogeneous data access and data management functionality. There are many other applications that are emerging based on the Sensor-Cloud infrastructure, which can be summarized as follows.]]></pText>
		</PageText>
		<PageText>
			<pText><![CDATA[
			<ol class="DecimalNumberClass">
				<li><b>Environmental Monitoring for Emergency or Disaster Detection</b>- In  environmental applications, it is possible to detect the earthquake and volcano explosion before its eruption by continuously monitoring them through the use of several numbers of different sensors like strain, temperature, light, image, sound, acceleration, barometer sensors and so forth through the use of Wireless Sensor Networks. Through the Sensor Cloud infrastructure, the sensor instances engaged in environmental monitoring can be used in parallel with several other sensor instances. For example the healthcare department can avoid any future casualty, or with crop harvesting application services they can avoid the damage caused by bad weather condition.</li>
				<li><b>Telematics</b> – Sensor Clouds can be used for telematics, meant to deploy the long distance transmission of our computerized or information to a system in continuum. It enables the smooth communication between system and devices without any intervention.</li>
				<li><b>Google Health</b> - It is a centralization service of Google that provides personal health information and serves as cloud health data storages. Google users are allowed to monitor their health records by logging into their accounts at collaborated cloud health service providers into the Google health system. However, in a recent declaration Google has announced the discontinuation of this health service.</li>
				<li><b>Microsoft HealthVault</b> - This cloud platform is developed by Microsoft to store and maintain health and fitness-related information. HealthVault helps users to store, gather and share their health relevant information and its data can be acquired from several pharmacies, cloud providers, health employees, health labs, equipment and from the users itself.</li>
				<li><b>Agriculture and Irrigation Control  (Field  Server  Sensors)</b>  – Sensor Cloud can be used in the field of agriculture to monitor the crop fields in order to upkeep it. For this, a field server is developed that comprises of a camera sensors, air sensor, temperature sensor, concentration sensor, soil moisture and temperature sensors and so forth. These sensors continuously upload the field data via Wi-Fi access point to the field owner to track the health of their crops. This can also be used for harvesting.</li>
				<li><b>Earth Observation</b> - A sensor grid is developed for data gathering from several GPS stations, to process, analyze, manage and visualize the GPS data. This GPS data would then be uploaded onto the cloud for efficient monitoring, early warning and decision-making capability for critical situations like the volcanic eruptions, earthquakes, tsunamis, cyclones and so forth to the users all around the world.</li>
				<li><b>Transportation and Vehicular Traffic Applications</b> – Sensor Cloud can be used to provide an efficient, stable, equilibrium and sustainable tracking system. Earlier existing technologies like GPS navigation can only track the status and current location of vehicle. On the other hand, when vehicle monitoring is implemented using cloud computing, it is possible to incorporate centralized web service, GPS and GSM enabled devices and embedded device with sensors which will provide the following benefits:
					<ol class="RomanLowerNumberClass">
						<li>To identify the current name of the location.</li>
						<li>To predict the time of arrival.</li>
						<li>To find status of driver via alcohol breath sensor.</li><li>To find the total distance covered.</li>
						<li>To track the level of fuel.</li>
					</ol>
				<li><b>Tunnel Monitoring</b> - WSN can be used to implement the distributed sensing of light levels inside the tunnel and under-bridges to provide necessary input information for adapting light functionality. This tunnel information can be put onto the cloud and is used to monitor the light intensity in real time to avoid the automobile users (drivers) casualty and to save the energy spent unnecessarily for lightening throughout the day.</li><li>Wildlife Monitoring – Sensor Cloud can also be used for tracking the wildlife sanctuaries, forests and so forth to regularly monitor the endangered species in real time.</li>
				<li><b>Wildlife Monitoring</b> – Sensor Cloud can also be used for tracking the wildlife sanctuaries, forests and so forth to regularly monitor the endangered species in real time.</li>
			</ol>]]>
			</pText>
		</PageText>
	</PageData>
</main>
