<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<main>
	<PageData>
	<MainHeading><![CDATA[]]></MainHeading>
		<SubHeading><![CDATA[11.4._Advantages of Sensor Cloud]]></SubHeading>
		<PageText>
			<pText><![CDATA[<ol class="DecimalNumberClass"><li><b>Analysis –</b> The integration of huge accumulated sensor data from several sensor networks and the cloud computing model make it attractive for various kinds of analysis required by users through provisioning of the scalable processing power.</li><li><b>Scalability</b> – Sensor Cloud enables the earlier sensor networks to scale on very large size because of the large routing architecture of cloud. It means that as the need for resources increases, organizations can scale or add the extra services from cloud computing vendors without having to invest heavily for these additional hardware resources.</li><li><b>Collaboration –</b> Sensor Cloud enables the huge sensor data to be shared by different groups of consumers through collaboration of various physical sensor networks. It eases the collaboration among several users and applications for huge data sharing on the cloud.</li><li><b>Visualization –</b> Sensor Cloud platform provide a visualization API to be used for representing the diagrams with the stored and retrieved sensor data from several device assets. Through the visualization tools, users can predict the possible future trends that have to be incurred.</li><li><b>Free Provisioning of Increased Data storage and Processing Power -</b> It provides free data storage and organizations may put their data rather than putting onto private computer systems without hassle. It provides enormous processing facility and storage resources to handle data of large-scale applications.</li><li><b>Dynamic Provisioning of Services –</b> Users of Sensor Cloud can access their relevant information from wherever they want and whenever they need rather than being stick to their desks.</li><li><b>Multitenancy –</b> The number of services from several service providers can be integrated easily through cloud and Internet for numerous service innovations to meet user’s demand. Sensor Cloud allows the accessibility to several numbers of data centers placed anywhere on the network world.</li><li>Automation – Automation played a vital role in provisioning of Sensor Cloud computing services. Automation of services improved the delivery time to a great extent.</li><li><b>Flexibility –</b> Sensor Cloud provides more flexibility to its users than the past computing methods. It provides flexibility to use random applications in any number of times and allows sharing of sensor resources under flexible usage environment.</li><li><b>Agility of Services –</b> Sensor Cloud provides agile services and the users can provision the expensive technological infrastructure resources with less cost. The integration of Wireless Sensor Networks with cloud allows the high-speed processing of data using immense processing capability of cloud.</li><li><b>Resource Optimization</b> – Sensor Cloud infrastructure enables the resource optimization by allowing the sharing of resources for several number of applications. The integration of sensors with cloud enables gradual reduction of resource cost and achieves higher gains of services. With Sensor-Cloud, both the small and midsized organizations can benefit from an enormous resource infrastructure without having to involve and administer it directly.</li><li><b>Quick Response Time –</b> The integration of WSN with cloud provides a very quick response to the user, that is, in real-time due to the large routing architecture of cloud. The quick response time of data feeds from several sensor networks or devices allows users to make critical decisions in near real time.</li></ol>]]></pText>
		</PageText>
	</PageData>
</main>
