<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<main>
	<PageData>
	<MainHeading><![CDATA[11_SENSOR CLOUD]]></MainHeading>
		<SubHeading><![CDATA[11.1._Introduction]]></SubHeading>
		<PageText>
		  <pText><![CDATA[The advancement and application of <span class="PageVideoClass" id="Video_BTNID" url="en/Video/Video_1.mp4" headername"Video">Wireless Sensor Networks</span> become an invincible trend into the various industrial, environmental and commercial fields. A typical sensor network may consist of a number of sensor nodes acting upon together to monitor a region and fetch data about the surroundings. A WSN contains spatially distributed self-regulated sensors that can cooperatively monitor the environmental conditions like sound, temperature, pressure, motion, vibration, pollution and so forth. Each node in a sensor network is loaded with a radio transceiver or some other wireless communication device, a small microcontroller and an energy source most often cells or battery. The nodes of sensor network have cooperative capabilities, which are usually deployed in a random manner. These sensor nodes basically consist of three parts: sensing, processing and communication. Some of the most common sensor devices deployed in sensor network as sensor nodes are camera sensor, accelerometer sensor, thermal sensor, microphone sensor and so forth. ]]></pText>
		</PageText>
		<PageText>
		  <pText><![CDATA[Currently, WSNs are being utilized in several areas like healthcare, defense such as military target tracking and surveillance, government and environmental services like natural disaster relief, hazardous environment exploration, seismic sensing and so forth. These sensors may provide various useful data when they are closely attached to each of their respective applications and services directly. However, sensor networks have to face many issues and challenges regarding their communications like short communication range, security and privacy, reliability, mobility, etc. and resources like power considerations, storage capacity, processing capabilities, bandwidth availability, etc. Besides, WSN has its own resource and design constraints. Design constraints are application specific and dependent on monitored environment. Based on the monitored environment, network size in WSN varies. For monitoring a small area, fewer nodes are required to form a network whereas the coverage of a very large area requires a huge number of sensor nodes. For monitoring large environment, there is limited communication between nodes due to obstructions into the environment, which in turn affects the overall network topology or connectivity. All these limitations on sensor networks would probably impede the service performance and quality. In the midst of these issues, the emergence of cloud computing is seen as a remedy. ]]></pText>
		</PageText>
		<PageText>
		  <pText><![CDATA[In a sensor network, the sensors are utilized by their specific application for a special purpose, and this application handles both the sensor data and the sensor itself such that other applications cannot use this. This makes wastage of valuable sensor resources that may be effectively utilized when integrating with other application’s infrastructure. To realize this scenario, Sensor-Cloud infrastructure is used that enables the sensors to be utilized on an IT infrastructure by virtualizing the physical sensor on a cloud computing platform. These virtualized sensors on a cloud computing platform are dynamic in nature and hence facilitate automatic provisioning of its services as and when required by users. Furthermore, users need not worry about the physical locations of multiple physical sensors and the gapping between physical sensors. Instead, they can supervise these virtual sensors using some standard functions.]]></pText>
		</PageText>
		<PageText>
		  <pText><![CDATA[Within the Sensor-Cloud infrastructure, to obtain QoS, the virtual sensors are monitored regularly so users can destroy their virtual sensors when they become meaningless. A user interface is provisioned by this Sensor-Cloud infrastructure for administering, that is, for controlling or monitoring the virtual sensors, provisioning and destroying virtual sensors, registering and deleting of physical sensors and for admitting the deleting users. For example, in a health monitoring environment, a patient may use a wearable computing system that may include wearable accelerometer sensors, proximity sensors, temperature sensors, etc. like Life Shirt and Smart Shirt or may use a handheld device loaded with sensors and consequently the data captured by the sensors may be made accessible to the doctors. But out of these computing systems, active continuous monitoring is most demanding, and it involves the patient wearing monitoring devices to obtain pervasive coverage without being inputted or intervened. ]]></pText>
		</PageText>
		<PageText>
		  <pText><![CDATA[Sensor modeling language (SML) can be used to represent any physical sensor’s metadata like their type, accuracy, physical location and so forth. It also uses Extensible Markup Language (XML) encoding for the measurement and description processes of physical sensors. This XML encoding for physical sensors enabled these to be implemented across several different hardware, platforms (OS), applications and so forth with relatively less human intervention. To transliterate the commands coming from users to virtual sensors and in turn to the commands for their pertinent physical sensors, a mapping is done between the physical and virtual sensors.]]></pText>
		</PageText>
	</PageData>
</main>
