<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<main>
	<PageData>
	<MainHeading><![CDATA[]]></MainHeading>
		<SubHeading><![CDATA[11.3._Sensor Cloud Architecture]]></SubHeading>
		<PageText>
			<pText><![CDATA[<a href="en\Resource\File_1.pdf" class="SectionClass" target="_blank">Cloud computing</a> service framework delivers the services of shared network through which the users are benefited by the services and they are not concerned with the implementation details of the services provided to them. When a user requests, the service instances (e.g., virtual sensors) generated by cloud computing services are automatically provisioned to them. ]]></pText>
		</PageText>
		<PageText>
			<pText><![CDATA[Users, other than their relevant sensor services, cannot use these physical sensors directly when needed. Therefore, these physical sensors should be supervised by some special sensor- management schemes. The Sensor Cloud infrastructure would subsidize the sensor system management, which ensures that the data-management usability of sensor resources would be fairly improved. ]]></pText>
		</PageText>
		<PageText>
			<pText><![CDATA[There exists no application that can make use of every kind of physical sensors at all times. Instead, each application required pertinent physical sensors for its fulfillment. To realize this concept, publish/subscription mechanism is being employed for choosing the appropriate physical sensor. In multiple sensor networks, every sensor network publishes its sensor data and metadata. The metadata comprises of the types, locations and so forth for the physical sensors. Application either subscribes to one or maybe to more sensor networks to retrieve real-time data from the physical sensors by allowing each application to opt for the appropriate physical sensors’ type. The Sensor Cloud infrastructure procreates virtual sensors from multiple physical sensors, which can then be utilized by users. However, prior to availing the virtual sensor facility, users should probe first for the physical sensor’s availability and might also inspect the physical sensor’s faults to maintain the data quality emerging from these physical sensors. Also on every sensor node, application program senses the application and sends the sensor data back to the gateway in the cloud directly through the base station or in multihop manner through other nodes.]]></pText>
		</PageText>
		<PageText>
			<pText><![CDATA[Sensor Cloud infrastructure provides service instances (virtual sensors) automatically to the end users as and when requested, in such a way that these virtual sensors are part of their IT resources (like disk storage, CPU, memory, etc.). These service instances and their associated appropriate sensor data can be used by the end users via a user interface through the web crawlers. Figure 11.3 shows the architecture of Sensor Cloud. ]]></pText>
		</PageText>
		<PageText>
			<pText><![CDATA[For the service instance generation, the IT resources (like CPU, storage devices, etc.), sensor capable devices and service templates (which is used to create virtual sensors) should be prepared first in Sensor Cloud infrastructure. Users make the request for service instances according to their needs by selecting an appropriate service template of Sensor Cloud, which will then provide the needed service instances freely and automatically because of cloud computing services integration. Once service instances become useless, they can then be deleted quickly by users to avoid the utilization charges for these resources. Sensor service provider will manage the service templates (ST) and it can add or delete the new service template when the required template is no longer needed by applications and services. Automation of services plays a vital role in provisioning of cloud computing services and automation can cause the delivery time of services to be better. Before the emergence of cloud computing, services were provided by human influence and the performance metrics like efficiency, flexibility, delivery times and so forth would have experienced an adverse effect on the system. However, the cloud computing service model has reduced the cost expenses and delivery time and has also improved the efficiency and flexibility.]]></pText>
		</PageText>
		<PageText>
			<pText><![CDATA[<div class="BigImgClass" style="text-align:center"><img src="en\images\Fig11.3.png"></div>]]></pText>
		</PageText>
		<PageText>
			<pText><![CDATA[The physical sensors are ranked on a basis of their sensor readings as well as on their actual distance from an event. Since the cloud computing enables the physical sensors to be virtualized, the users of the Sensor Cloud infrastructure need not worry about the status of their connected physical sensors (i.e., whether a fault free or not). However, they should concern only with the status of their virtual sensors provided only when the users are not concerned with the accurate results. To achieve accurate results, users must be concerned about the status of physical sensors too. In a Sensor Cloud infrastructure, sensor owners are free to register or unregister their physical sensors and can join this infrastructure. These IT resources (physical sensors, database servers, processors, etc.) and sensor devices are then prepared to become operational. After that, templates are created for generating the service instances (virtual sensors) and its groups (virtual sensors). Once templates are prepared, the virtual sensors are able to share the related and contiguous physical sensors to receive quality sensor data. Users then request these virtual sensors by choosing the appropriate service templates, use their service instances (virtual sensors) after being provisioned and discharge them when became useless.]]></pText>
		</PageText>
	</PageData>
</main>
